Sergio Villarroel

Full Stack Software Engineer

| sergioworking247@gmail.com |

707-440-9693

www.sergiodev.com

github.com/sergiov13

Web Developer and QA Developer with a strong background in Software engineering with 5+ years of experience. I've been involved in every step of web and software development implementing agile and scrum methodologies and generating extensive documentation of tests and results. Skilled in automated testing and creating test plans. My previous employments provided me with experiences and multiple skills that allow me to effectively communicate remotely with other team members and clients to achieve goals and achieve customer satisfaction.

Relevant Experience

Web Developer @ Freelance

April 2020 - Present // Sacramento, CA

- Write modern, performant and robust code for a diverse array of clients and internal projects.
- Work with a variety of different languages, frameworks and content management systems such as JavaScript, React, Django, Node.JS. Python, Selenium, etc.
- Communicate and collaborate with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, clients on a daily basis

Java Developer & QA Developer @ Accenture

May 2017 - April 2020 // Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Led a small team focused on developing a testing tool based in python, Selenium web Driver which applied a light layer of Machine Learning and Database feedback for testing new implementations automatically.
- Modified existing software of Oracle's billing and customer care application using Java, Hibernate and spring to correct bugs along with improving performance and upgrading interfaces.
- Worked closely with Project Manager in a successful migration backing up databases, restoring and updating the billing application for a major Argentinian energy company.

SAP Consultant @ IBM

May 2014 - December 2016 // Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Consulted with clients regularly regarding projects, proposals, and technical issues that arise during the development process, while collaborating with other team members to determine the best design specifications and application of solutions.
- Designed and mapped internal workflows for legal, planning and confidential documents, and developed a file management system.
- Prepared reports on specifications and activities for each project.
- Quickly learned Abap and provided support finding bugs and developing new solutions.

Skills

Programming Languages

Python, Java, Javascript (ES6), GraphQL, MySQL, CSS, HTML, Bash, Shell Scripting.

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Gatsby, Node.JS, Django, Spring, Hibernate, Selenium

Tools & Platforms

Git, Webpack, Netlify, AWS, Firebase, Docker, Trello, Jenkins, Windows and Linux

Education

UADE

(Argentinian University of Business) 2016 - 2022

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science.

Courses

Automation with Python (by Google). QA Testing of software solutions. Advanced Java (Threads, 00,

Hibernate, Java EE, JSP, JSF. Maven Web Applications.

Projects

Servlets).

Music Rooms:

Web App built with Django, React and spotify API where you can create and join a room with a unique code and vote for next song or to skip songs.

Interests

Photography, Outdoor activities, Reading, Traveling and new technologies.

Languages

English (Native) Spanish (Native)